<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.ldtk.LDtk</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.ldtk.LDtk.desktop</launchable>
  <name>LDtk</name>
  <summary>Modern, lightweight and efficient 2D level editor</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <developer_name>Sébastien Bénard</developer_name>
  <url type="homepage">https://ldtk.io</url>
  <description>
    <p>A modern 2D level editor from the creator of Dead Cells, with a strong focus on user-friendliness.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Easy to use: Every UI details were carefully designed to make the process of creating levels as smooth as possible.</li>
      <li>Super Simple Export: For every new tool out there, there is this moment when you need to write the importer for your fav engine. I’ve been there too: so LDtk offers a Super Simple Export option. And by “simple”, I mean it.</li>
      <li>Auto-rendering: Define some simple rules in a visual editor and let LDtk do the boring part of the skinning job for you.</li>
      <li>World editor: Choose your world layout among “Grid-vania”, “linear”, or “free” and reorganize all your levels using plain old simple drag-n-drop.</li>
      <li>Entities: Create your own game entities, with any custom (typed) properties, like “hit points”, a patrol path or an inventory of items.</li>
      <li>Aseprite support: LDtk can load “*.aseprite” files directly, without any whatsoever intermediate PNG conversion. And with live-reloading support, you paint your tiles, save and LDtk updates everything accordingly, including image resizing.</li>
      <li>Side &amp; top-downs: LDtk focuses on these perspectives to make sure the user experience feels just right. Sorry, no isometric here!</li>
      <li>JSON: The app outputs a well documented JSON format that you can easily parse in your favorite game engine.</li>
      <li>Tiled export: Tiled (TMX) optional export to try it out before implementing your own importer.</li>
      <li>Backups: We know bad things can happen. LDtk offers a strong backup system and can even restore unsaved changes if the app crashes. Which shouldn’t happen, but we don’t live in a perfect world.</li>
      <li>Pay what you want! LDtk can be used for free without any limitation. But if you want to support my work, please consider buying it, or becoming a direct sponsor.</li>
      <li>Optional Haxe API: If you are a Haxe user, you can benefit from a powerful and fully typed Haxe API, generated by macros as you type.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>General editor UI</caption>
      <image type="source">https://ldtk.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/mainUI.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Application home screen</caption>
      <image type="source">https://ldtk.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/home.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>World view</caption>
      <image type="source">https://ldtk.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/worldView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Platformer example</caption>
      <image type="source">https://ldtk.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/platformer.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Provided examples will showcase various LDtk functionalities</caption>
      <image type="source">https://ldtk.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sample.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Entities are highly customizable and powerful</caption>
      <image type="source">https://ldtk.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/entities.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.4.1" date="2023-09-25"/>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
